<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kenneth&#39;s Notepad</title>
    <link>https://kfeng.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kenneth&#39;s Notepad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020 Kenneth Feng.  All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 22:21:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kfeng.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Bazel version consistent with Bazelisk</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/2020/05/keep-bazel-version-consistent-with-bazelisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 22:21:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/2020/05/keep-bazel-version-consistent-with-bazelisk/</guid>
      <description>Bazel Bazel is a build system, which allows you to build and test source code written in many programming languages and other things such as Protocol Buffer. Keeping bazel version consistent across developer machines and continuous integration machines is challenging. Often, a continuous integration machine is running an older version of bazel. The bazel installation on the CI machine needs to be managed by someone who has privilege to install software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading pip from v1.4.1</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/2016/11/upgrading-pip-from-v1.4.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 06:21:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/2016/11/upgrading-pip-from-v1.4.1/</guid>
      <description>Story pip-v1.4.1 is installed by default when used with virtualenv on CentOS 6. In a production environment, it is preferred to upgrade pip offline. But, upgrading pip via pip install --upgrade &amp;lt;local-pip.whl&amp;gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. If you had a virtualenv named env, it would remove env/bin/pip after the upgrade install. After hours of testing, it appears that, instead of using a pip wheel, a source distribution tar.gz would work. pip install --upgrade pip-9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Gotcha</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/2015/09/golang-gotcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 10:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/2015/09/golang-gotcha/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I ran into a Go gotcha which took me a while to figure it out. Basically, I have the following code that prints out an item from a list of integers. The item is being closed by a function closure inside the for loop.
As you can see, this code looks perfectly normal for a Go beginner like me.
Apparently, it was wrong because the temporary variable, v used in the for loop is being reused by the loop itself for Every iteration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker for Development</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/2015/04/using-docker-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 23:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/2015/04/using-docker-for-development/</guid>
      <description>For the purpose of this article, we are going to assume we have a web application which needs a postgres database as the backend. With the power of docker and docker compose, we can quickly spin up the database quickly.
Let&amp;rsquo;s just say you already have the following Production Dockerfile configured.
FROM kennethzfeng/dockerize-python:2.7.8-onbuild EXPOSE 8000 ENV APPLICATION_ENV Production CMD [&amp;quot;gunicorn&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;app:app&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;--worker-class&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;gevent&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;-b&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;0.0.0.0:8000&amp;quot;] You need to create a development version of Dockerfile called it something like Dockerfile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Create Javascript Classes</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/2014/08/dynamically-create-javascript-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 22:13:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/2014/08/dynamically-create-javascript-classes/</guid>
      <description>Problem Recently, I was asked to think of a way to dynamically create classes, which have static methods that are slightly different among dynamically created classes.
Solution I used a factory-like function to generate class with a static method that closes on the parameter name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profile</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Work Experience Software Engineer @ Yext | March 2017 - PresentSystems Engineer @ Yext | June 2016 - February 2017Business Systems Developer @ Intermedia | January 2015 - June 2016Business Systems Analyst @ Intermedia | May 2013 - December 2014
  Build and maintain Mulesoft Cloudhub integrations with NetSuite (ERP), Salesforce (CRM), Coupa, Marketo, MS SQL Server using Java / Spring Framework
  Design and support internal tools hosted on the Finance IT application server:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips</title>
      <link>https://kfeng.me/pages/tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfeng.me/pages/tips/</guid>
      <description>Archive rpm package is a cpio archive.
zip -r ../target.zip * - zip recrusively all the content under the current directory to the target.zip
unzip -l /path/to/a.zip - list the content of the zip file
Fails a bash script on error set -e</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>